italia.it 2015-11-21

# Information on the protection of privacy

This information describes the way in which the italia.it website processes the personal information of users who consult it. 

This information is also provided, in accordance with Art. 13 of Decree No. 196 dated 30 June 2003, "Code for the protection of personal information", to those who interact with the web services accessible via the Internet from the following URL address: [www.italia.it](http://www.italia.it/)

The information provided only relates to the www.italia.it website and not to any other websites that might be consulted by the user when following links. 

Pursuant to Art. 13 of the above law, the following information is provided with regard to the processing of your personal data. 

## Types of Data

**Dati di registrazione**   
The information requested at the time of registration will be used to allow access to and use of certain online services. 

**Browsing Data (log files)**   
In the normal course of operations, the IT systems and software applications dedicated to the functioning of this website acquire certain personal information whose transmission is inherent to the use of Internet communications protocols. 

Such information is not gathered for association with identified interested parties but, by its nature, might allow users to be identified via further processing and association with information held by third parties. 

This category of information includes the IP addresses and domain names of the computers used to access the website, the URI (Uniform Resource Identifier) addresses of the resources required, the time of the request, the method used to make the request to the server, the size of the file obtained in reply, the numeric code indicating the status of the reply sent by the server (ok, error, etc.) and other parameters relating to the operating system and the user's IT environment. 

Such information is only used to obtain anonymous statistical information about the use of the website and to check that it is functioning correctly; it is kept for the period of time required by law. This information could be used to determine responsibility for any hypothetical IT crime committed to the detriment of the website. 

**Cookies**   
Cookies are not used for the transmission of personal information and no persistent cookies (systems for tracking users) of any kind are used. 

The use of session cookies (which are not saved in a persistent manner on the user's computer and vanish when the browser is closed) is strictly limited to the transmission of the ID session (random number generated by the server) required for the safe and efficient browsing of the website. 

The session cookies used by this website do not make recourse to other IT techniques that might be detrimental to the privacy of browsing by users, and they do not allow the acquisition of personal data identifying the user. 

## Purpose of Processing

The personal information provided by you may be processed, directly and/or by third parties, solely for the following purposes:

  1. a) purposes strictly related to and necessary for the use of the website and the services requested; 
  2. b) purposes linked to the performance of market research, economic and statistical analyses, the provision of information and updates on the initiatives and plans of Italia.it. 

## Methods of Processing

The handling of personal information includes the gathering, recording, organisation, conservation, processing, modification, selection, extraction, comparison, use, interconnection, block, communication, spread, deletion and destruction of such information, as well as the combination of two or more of the above operations. 

Personal information is processed for the purposes referred to above, in accordance with the provisions of Art. 11 of Decree No. 196/2003, using paper, IT and telecommunications support administered via electronic or other automated equipment, in compliance with the privacy and security rules envisaged by current regulations. 

Processing is carried out directly by the Processing Owner's organisation, as well as by external companies that provide various services for the purposes referred to in the above point. 

The information is retained for a period of time that does not exceed that necessary for the purposes for which it was collected or subsequently processed in accordance with legal requirements. 

## Nature of the Provision of Personal Information and Consequences of any Refusal to Reply

The provision of personal information is optional. Any refusal to provide such information may make it impossible to use the website or certain services. 

## Communication and Spreading of Information

In compliance with current regulations, the information may be communicated to external companies that perform activities in support of the services and information requested, by taking part in our business processes and/or by providing services of various kinds, such as maintenance and support for the website and related services. Personal information will not generally be made available. 

## Rights of Interested Parties

Interested parties have the right to obtain confirmation of the existence, or otherwise, of any personal information held that relates to them, even if not yet recorded, and to receive such information in an intelligible form. 

Interested parties are entitled to receive the following information:

  1. a) the source of the personal information; 
  2. b) the ways in which it is processed and the related purposes; 
  3. c) the logic used if processing is carried out using electronic equipment; 
  4. d) details identifying the processing owner and managers as well as the representative appointed pursuant to Art. 5, Para. 2 of Decree No. 196/2003; 
  5. e) the parties or categories of parties to which the personal information may be communicated or which may become aware of it in their capacity as the appointed representative for the Nation, as managers or as authorised personnel. 

Interested parties are entitled to demand:

  1. a) the update or correction of their information or, when desired, the addition of extra information; 
  2. b) the deletion, the transformation into an anonymous form or block on information processed in violation of the law, including the information which need not be retained having regard for the purposes for which such information was gathered or subsequently processed; 
  3. c) confirmation that the operations referred to in points a) and b), and their content, have been drawn to the attention of those to whom the information has been communicated or spread, except if this turns out to be impossible or would require the use of resources that are clearly disproportionate with respect to the protected rights. 

Interested parties have the right to object, in whole or in part:

  1. a) for legitimate reasons, to the processing of their personal information, even if such information is pertinent to the purposes for which it was gathered; 
  2. b) to the processing of their personal information for the purposes of sending advertising or direct marketing materials, or for market research or commercial communications. 

## Processing Owners and Managers

Pursuant to Art. 13 of Decree No. 196/2003, the Processing Owner for the information is the Presidency of the Council - Minister of Tourism - with registered offices at Via della Ferratella in Laterano n. 51, Rome; the external manager for the processing of the information is ACI - Automobile Club d'Italia - with registered offices at Via Marsala n. 8, Rome. 

The party to be contacted for the exercise of the above rights is the Manager. 

The "Privacy Policy" of this website, described above, is subject to future updates.
